A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Issue Books, Series 17 FA363
Rockefeller Archive Center
- 1964 Presidential Election, 1959-1964; 1; 9.2 Cubic Feet
  - Volume 50 - Transportation, 1959-1964 (Box 20, Folder 118)
    Tab 38 Evaluation of Kuchel Survey of Goldwater Votes, Transportation, May 12, 1964
    Tab 39 "As A Republican, I Believe... " Economic Growth: The Free Enterprise System, April 15, 1964 -- section pertaining to free enterprise from published brochure of NAR positions on issues affecting the United States and the Republican Party.
    Tab 40 Platform Analysis Notebook, Economy: Transportation, May 14, 1964
    Tab 41 NAR Submission to Republican Platform Committee, Republican Program for Domestic Policy, July 7, 1964
  - Volume 51 - Housing and Urban Affairs, 1959-1964 (Box 21, Folder 119)
    Tab 1 Background Paper No. M-4, Housing and Urban Renewal, January 1960 -- paper written by Robinson Newcomb Associates.
    Tab 2 Summary Paper No. M-4, Housing and Urban Renewal, February 10, 1960 -- paper written by Robinson Newcomb Associates.
    Tab 3 Position Paper No. M-4, Housing and Urban Development and Redevelopment, June 11, 1960 -- paper written by Rod Perkins.
    Tab 4 Short Summaries of Position Papers, Housing and Urban Development and Redevelopment, June 11, 1960
    Tab 5 Draft Platform Plank, Housing, June 19-21, 1960 -- prepared by Rod Perkins and E. Hughes.
    Tab 6 Comparison of Republican and Democratic Platforms (R. B. Perkins Platform Analysis), Housing and Urban Affairs, September 7, 1960
    Tab 7 1960 Campaign Analysis, Housing, November 30, 1960
    Tab 8 Memorandum, Metropolitan Areas, December 28, 1960 -- Rod Perkins memo on the report of the Regional Plan Association (New York City).
    Tab 9 Memorandum, Department of Urban Affairs, April 18, 1961 -- Mary K. Boland memo on suggested NAR position on proposed Department of Urban Affairs.
    Tab 10 Background Paper, Housing Act of 1961, October 16, 1961 -- Rod Perkins paper on the Kennedy Administration record in Housing.
    Tab 11 Summary of the State of the Union Message, Urban Affairs, January 18, 1962
  - Volume 51 - Housing and Urban Affairs, 1959-1964 (Box 21, Folder 120)
    Tab 12 Memorandum, Department of Urban Affairs: NAR Statements and Kennedy Position, February 6, 1962 -- suggested NAR positions in contrast to positions held by the Kennedy Administration.
    Tab 13 Memorandum, Recommended Position on Department of Urban Affairs, February 6, 1962
    Tab 14 Memorandum, Supplemental History on PACGO Proposal for HHFA and FCDA, February 7, 1962 -- Rod Perkins memo on plan by the Presidential Advisory Committee on Governmental Organization (PACGO) concerning the Housing and Home Finance Agency (HHFA) and the Federal Civil Defense Administration (FCDA).
    Tab 15 Draft Statement, Department of Urban Affairs, February 10, 1962 -- two suggested NAR positions on the proposed government department.
    Tab 16 NAR Interview, "Issues and Answers," Department of Urban Affairs, February 11, 1962 -- transcript of NAR appearance on the television program.
    Tab 17 NAR Press Conference, Department of Urban Affairs, February 14, 1962 -- questions posed to NAR concerning his position on the proposed government department.
    Tab 18 NAR Statement, Department of Urban Affairs, February 15, 1962 -- transcript of NAR speech delivered at the Association of Towns Annual Luncheon, Buffalo, New York.
    Tab 19 Suggested Outline for NAR Speech, The Republican Party and the Urban Dweller, April 18, 1962 -- notes prepared in advance of NAR speech to GOP women.
    Tab 20 Current Positions Notebook, Housing and Urban Development, May 9, 1962
    Tab 21 Position Papers, NAR Meeting with New York Republican Congressional Delegation, June 27, 1962 -- position papers for NAR on Urban Affairs to be used in meeting with the New York State Republican Congressional Delegation.
    Tab 22 Memorandum, Senator Mansfield's Statement Concerning Defeat of Urban Affairs and Medicare, October 10, 1962
    Tab 23 Current Positions Card, Housing and Urban Affairs, October 22, 1962
    Tab 24 "Rockefeller on the Issues," Housing, Summary by B. Jones of NAR Stated Positions, September 1963
    Tab 25 Draft Policy Paper, Housing and Urban Affairs, November 1, 1963 -- paper submitted by New York State Housing Finance Agency Assistant Director Lee Goodwin.
    Tab 26 NAR Quotes for "Christian Science Monitor" Interview, Housing and Urban Affairs, November 8, 1963
    Tab 27 Background Paper, Federal Government Activities Relating to Housing, December 26, 1963 -- paper submitted by Robinson Newcomb and Associates.
    Tab 28 Summary Position, Housing and Urban Affairs, December 1963
  - Volume 52 - Housing and Urban Affairs, 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 121)
    Tab 29 Supplements to Background Paper of December 26, 1963, Federal Government Activities Relating to Housing, January 10, 1964 -- paper submitted by Robinson Newcomb and Associates.
    Tab 30 Background Information for Meeting on Metropolitan Areas, January 15, 1964
    Tab 31 Substantive Comments on November 1st Policy Paper, January 18, 1964 -- paper submitted by Robinson Newcomb and Associates.
    Tab 32 Telephone Message from Roswell Perkins to Dr. Ronan, LBJ Proposal for Department of Housing and Community Development, January 29, 1964 -- suggested NAR response to President Johnson's plan to create new federal department.
    Tab 33 Letter from Roswell Perkins to R. Mort Frayne and Memorandum of Fact, NAR Position on Department of Urban Affairs, February 15, 1964
    Tab 34 A Comparison on Domestic Issues of Taft, Rockefeller, and Goldwater, Housing, April 1964 -- campaign brochure outlining positions held by Senator Robert A. Taft (R-Ohio), Senator Barry Goldwater (R-Arizona), and NAR.
    Tab 35 Outline of Domestic "White Paper" #4, an Urban America, April 3, 1964
    Tab 36 "As A Republican, I Believe... " An Urban America, May 11, 1964 -- section pertaining to urban issues from published brochure of NAR positions on issues affecting the United States and the Republican Party.
    Tab 37 Evaluation of Kuchel Survey of Goldwater Votes, Research in Housing for the Aged, May 11, 1964
    Tab 38 Memorandum, Department of Urban Affairs, May 13, 1964
    Tab 39 Platform Analysis Notebook, Housing, May 14, 1964
    Tab 40 Draft Policy Statement, An Urban America, May 22, 1964
    Tab 41 Draft Plank for 1964 GOP Platform, Meeting the Needs of an Urban America, June 4, 1964
    Tab 42 Model Platform, Meeting the Nees of an Urban America, June 18, 1964
    Tab 43 Draft Platform Plank, Meeting the Needs of an Urban America, June 25, 1964
    Tab 44 NAR Submission to Republican Platform Committee, Urban Affairs, July 7, 1964
    Tab 45 "Moderate" Plank, Submitted to Platform Committee, Urban Affairs, July 7, 1964 and Background Material on Plank, Urban Affairs, July 9, 1964
    Tab 46 "I Take My Stand" by William Scranton, for Help to Our Cities, July 12, 1964
    Tab 47 General Statement of Minority Views to 1964 GOP Platform, Urban Affairs, July 13, 1964
  - Volume 53 - Welfare, Anti-Poverty Program, 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 122)
    Tab 1 Draft Press Release for New York on Johnson Poverty Program, February 19, 1964
    Tab 2 Poverty Meeting, March 17, 1964 -- notes from meeting with Chase Bank staff.
    Tab 3 Papers Proposing an Alternative to the Johnson Anti-Poverty Program, March 23, 1964 -- papers prepared by Justine Rodriguez, Chase Manhattan Bank.
    Tab 4 Summary of Johnson Poverty Program and Recommended Positions, March 23, 1964 -- contains a summary of program proposals, suggested general position, specific criticisms, and a cost Summary.
    Tab 5 NAR Remarks on Poverty Program, April 20, 1964 -- excerpt from NAR speech delivered in San Diego, California.
    Tab 6 Memorandum, Johnson Poverty Program and Appalachia, April 26, 1964 -- Rod Perkins memo on the Johnson Administration's plans for poverty and the region of Appalachia.
    Tab 7 Cost Summary, Poverty Program, April 26, 1964
    Tab 8 Cost Summary, Appalachia Program, April 28, 1964
    Tab 9 Summary of Appalachia Programs, April 29, 1964
    Tab 10 Memorandum, Analysis of State Role in Administration of Poverty Program, May 6, 1964 -- Rod Perkins memo on the role of the states in the poverty program as proposed by the Johnson Administration.
    Tab 11 Special Addendum on Poverty, developed for Platform Analysis Notebook, May 14, 1964
    Tab 12 Draft Plank for Republican Platform, Welfare and Social Security, June 19-21, 1960
    Tab 13 Comparison of Republican and Democratic Platforms (R. B. Perkins Platform Analysis), Health and Welfare, September 7, 1960
    Tab 14 Memorandum, Federal Social Security Legislation, 1961, September 21, 1961 -- Rod Perkins memo on suggested NAR position.
    Tab 15 Summary of Proposals in State of the Union, Welfare, January 18, 1962
    Tab 16 Memorandum, Day Care Services, March 29, 1962 -- suggested NAR position on adopting state organized day care services.
    Tab 17 Draft Speech on Welfare, Child Welfare, and Rehabilitation, October 11, 1962
    Tab 18 Current Positions Card, Welfare, October 22, 1962
    Tab 19 "Rockefeller on the Issues," Public Welfare, Summary by B. Jones of NAR Stated Positions, September 1963
    Tab 20 Questions and Answers for "U.S. News & World Report" Interview, Welfare, September 5, 1963 -- specific questions on welfare posed to NAR as part of interview with the news magazine.
    Tab 21 Draft Background Paper, Welfare, September 30,k 1963
    Tab 22 NAR Quotes for "Christian Science Monitor" Interview, Welfare, November 8, 1963
  - Volume 53 - Welfare - Anti-Poverty Program/Social Security and Public Assistance, 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 123)
    Welfare - Anti-Poverty Program
    Tab 23 Comments upon Public Indigency Problems in the United States in Relation to Senator Goldwater's Positions on Public Welfare, November 14, 1963 -- statement by Commissioner George K. Wyman.
    Tab 24 Summary Position Paper, Health and Welfare, December 1963
    Tab 25 Memorandum to Campaign Staff, NAR's Achievements at HEW, January 3, 1964 -- Rod Perkins memo on expanded text of "Meet Nelson Rockefeller," rewritten to include NAR's HEW tenure.
    Tab 26 Chart Showing Effect of Goldwater Position on Social Security, January 1964
    Tab 27 NAR Statement, Welfare, January 9, 1964 -- delivered at Manchester, New Hampshire.
    Tab 28 NAR One-Minute Spots, Social Security, January 18, 1964
    Tab 29 NAR One-Minute Spots, Welfare, January 18, 1964
    Tab 30 NAR Statement, Social Security, February 19, 1964 -- delivered at Rochester, New Hampshire.
    Welfare - Social Security and Public Assistance
    Tab 31 NAR Radio and Television Spot, Social Security, February 26, 1964
    Tab 32 Draft Press Release, Social Security, February 26, 1964
    Tab 33 NAR Statement, Social Security, February 28, 1964 -- delivered at Keene, New Hampshire.
    Tab 34 Answers to Questions of "Manchester (N.H.) Union-Leader," Social Security, February 29, 1964 -- NAR response to question on Social Security as posed by New Hampshire newspaper.
    Tab 35 Background Paper, Social Security and Welfare, March 1964 -- paper written by Gloria Klopman.
    Tab 36 Domestic White Paper #5, Older Americans: Social Security, March 17, 1964
    Tab 37 A Comparison on Domestic Issues of Taft, Rockefeller, and Goldwater, Social Security, April 1964 -- campaign brochure outlining positions held by Senator Robert A. Taft, (R-Ohio), Senator Barry Goldwater (R-Arizona), and NAR.
    Tab 38 Memorandum, Affirmative Social Security Program, April 15, 1964 -- Rod Perkins memo of suggested NAR positive position on Social Security.
    Tab 39 Draft Policy Statement, Social Security, April 15, 1964
    Tab 40 Draft NAR Statement, Social Security, April 19, 1964
    Tab 41 "As A Republican, I Believe... " Opportunities and Care for the Aged, May 11, 1964 -- section pertaining to aged issues from published brochure of NAR positions on issues affecting the United States and the Republican Party.
    Tab 42 Platform Analysis Notebook, Older Citizens, May 14, 1964
    Tab 43 Draft Platform Planks, Opportunities and Care for the Aged, June 5, 1964
    Tab 44 Draft Model Platform, Older Persons, June 18, 1964
    Tab 45 Evaluation of Goldwater "Blue Book," Social Security, June 19, 1964
    Tab 46 Draft Platform Planks, Social Security, June 25, 1964
    Tab 47 Draft "One-Page" Planks, Opportunities and Care for the Aged, June 30, 1964
    Tab 48 Possible Paragraphs to be Inserted in Platform, Social Security, July 1, 1964
    Tab 49 Revised Set of Platform Planks, Older Persons, July 6, 1964
    Tab 50 NAR Submission to the Platform Committee, Aged, July 7, 1964
    Tab 51 Moderate Platform Plank, Social Security, July 10, 1964
  - Volume 54, 1959-1964 (Box 22, Folder 124)
    Abuse of Power, 1961-1964
    Tab 1 NAR Statement, "On the Need to Restrain the Abuse of Federal Power," October 11, 1963 -- delivered at the Indiana Bar Association Convention, French Lick, Indiana.
    Tab 2 Draft Statement, "The Issue of Executive Secrecy," February 12, 1964 -- paper written by Rod Perkins and A. Abrahams.
    Communications Satellites, 1961-1964
    Tab 3 Current Position Notebook, Communications Satellites, September 19, 1962
    Tab 4 Memorandum, Kennedy Communications Satellites Program, February 28, 1964 -- outline of the Kennedy Administration proposal for a communications satellite program.
    Consumers, 1961-1964
    Tab 5 Outline for Position Paper, Kennedy Program on Consumer Interests, August 15, 1962
    Tab 6 Memorandum, Quality Stabilization Act, November 21, 1963 -- Richard Nathan memo on suggested NAR position on quality stabilization legislation.
    Extremism, 1961-1964
    Tab 7 Memorandum, Monday Press Conference, August 2, 1963 -- John Deardourff memo on possible questions on Barry Goldwater and right-wing extremism that may be posed to NAR.
    Tab 8 NAR Statement in "Christian Science Monitor," Extremism, November 8, 1963
    Tab 9 Answers to "The Monitor" Questionnaire, Extremism, May 7, 1964 -- selected questions on the threat of extremism posed to NAR by the California Catholic newspaper.
    Tab 10 Revised Set of Platform Planks, Extremism, June 30, 1964
    Tab 11 NAR Statement, Extremism, July 17, 1964
    Government Organization, 1959-1960
    Tab 12 Background Paper, "Chief Issues of Federal Executive Branch Organization," n.d. -- paper written by J. Kieffer, University of Oregon.
    Tab 13 NAR Statement, the Federal System, June 21, 1960 -- delivered at the Binghamton Rotary Club Luncheon, Binghamton, New York.
    Tab 14 Memorandum, Editorial Reaction to "First Secretary" Proposal, July 6, 1960 -- Mary Boland memo on the editorials published in response to the proposal to create a "First Secretary" position within the federal government.
    Tab 15 NAR Statement, Subcommittee on National Policy Machinery of the Senate Committee on Government Organization, July 1960 -- transcript from the "Congressional Record" of NAR testimony before the subcommittee.
    Tab 16 "A Republican Approach to Great Issues," Government Reorganization, July 11, 1960
    Tab 17 Letter from [US Senator] Jacob Javits, July 25, 1960 -- letter to Rod Perkins on NAR's proposal for a position of "First Secretary."
    Tab 18 Memorandum, Views of Ralph I. Stratus on State Department Reorganization, August 1960 -- summary of Stratus paper on a reorganization of the United States State Department.
    Immigration, 1961-1964
    Tab 19 Memorandum, Draft Statement on Immigration, January 1964
    Tab 20 Background Paper, Immigration, February 25, 1964 -- paper written by Thomas Lumbard.
    Tab 21 Platform Analysis Notebook, Immigration, May 1964
  - Volume 54, 1959-1964 (Box 22, Folder 125)
    Juvenile Delinquency and Crime, 1961-1964
    Tab 22 Current Position Notebook, Juvenile Delinquency, July 27, 1962
    Tab 23 Outline, Position Paper, Crime, July 1962
    Tab 24 Background Paper, Crime, January 1964
    Tab 25 Outline, Domestic White Paper #7, Combatting Crime, April 3, 1964
    Tab 26 Memorandum, Background Paper on the Compensation of Victims of Crimes of Violence, April 9, 1964 -- paper written by Sharon Gross in response to a British plan to launch an experimental program of compensating victims of violent crime.
    Tab 27 Memorandum, DOmestic White Paper #7, Combatting Crime, May 15, 1964
    Tab 28 Draft, Combating Crime and the Administration of Criminal Justice, May 19, 1964
    Presidential Succession, 1961-1964
    Tab 29 Memorandum, Presidential Succession, January 19, 1964 -- suggested NAR responses to questions on suggested changes to the Presidential Succession Act.
    Tab 30 NAR Statement, Text of Letter to Senator Birch Evan Bayh, Jr., February 26, 1964
    Tab 31 NAR Statement, Text of Letter to President Lyndon Johnson, February 27, 1964
    Tab 32 Fact Sheet, "Presidential Succession: Need for Action," April 28, 1964
    Tab 33 NAR Statement, May 20, 1964
    School Prayer, 1961-1964
    Tab 34 Memorandum, "Possible Constitutional Amendment on School Prayer," November 4, 1963 -- Rod Perkins memo on New Hampshire and New England feelings of a constitutional amendment regarding school prayer.
    Tab 35 Memorandum, School Prayer, November 23, 1963
    Tab 36 Summary Position, School Prayer, December 1963
    Tab 37 Question and Recommended Position on School Prayer, January 13, 1964
    Tab 38 Draft, "Proposed Reply to Inquiry as to Position on School Prayer," January 13, 1964
    Tab 39 Memorandum, School Prayer, January 27, 1964
    Tab 40 Draft Reply Letter, School Prayer, February 3, 1964
    Tab 41 Draft Statement, "The School Prayer Question," March 19, 1964
    Tab 42 Answers to "The Monitor" Questionnaire, School Prayer, May 7, 1964 -- selected question on school prayer posed to NAR by the California Catholic newspaper.
    Small Business, 1961-1964
    Tab 43 Draft Statement, Small Business, December 28, 1963
    Tab 44 Second Draft Statement, Small Business, January 4, 1964
    Tab 45 NAR Statement, "Helping Small Business Grow," January 1964
    Tab 46 Memorandum, Small Business Statement, January 19, 1964 -- Rod Perkins memo on drafting of pamphlet on NAR position on small businesses.
    Tab 47 Pamphlet, "Helping Small Business Grow"
    Tab 48 Memorandum, "Reaction to Small Business Statement," February 18, 1964 -- Rod Perkins memo including text of letter written to Hugh Morrow after NAR issued statement on small business.
    Tab 49 NAR Statement, "Helping Small Business Grow," February 20, 1964 -- column prepared for New Hampshire newspapers, under the headline, "As Rockefeller Sees It."
  - Volume 6 - General Materials (duplicate copy) (Box 22, Folder 126)
  - Volume 7 - General Materials (duplicate copy) (Box 23, Folder 127)
  - Volume 34 - Agriculture (duplicate copy) (Box 23, Folder 128)
- First Gubernatorial Term, 1958-1962; 2; 5.4 Cubic Feet
  The volumes in this subseries contain memoranda from Governor Rockefeller's staff and advisors focused on New York State issues. Primarily the subseries is composed of statements and speeches made by Governor Rockefeller on issues affecting New York, one of the country's most populous states. Of note in this subseries are press releases issued by the Governor's office of "Veto Memorandum" to indicate why the Governor chose not to sign an Assembly or Senate bill into law. There are also copies of enacted legislation. Also found in this subseries are a number of campaign statements issued by the Rockefeller campaign prior to the 1958 election. At the end of each year are summaries prepared by staff that denote accomplishments achieved by the administration on the various issues.
  - Volume 1 - The Aging, 1958-1962 (Box 24, Folder 129)
    Tab 1 Background Paper: Four Years of Legislative Achievement in Behalf of the Aged (1955-1958) -- prepared by Albert Adams, n.d.
    Tab 2 Background Paper: Aging in New York State -- Roswell B. Perkins, June 26, 1958.
    Tab 3 Notes on Aging -- Roswell B. Perkins, August 29, 1958.
    Tab 4 Fact Sheet, The Aging (Republican Record, 1943-1956), prepared by the Republican Legislative Research Staff, 1958.
    Tab 5 Fact Sheet, The Aging (Republican Record, 1943-1958), prepared by the Republican Legislative Research Staff, 1958.
    Tab 6 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpt from October 13, 1958, Policy Statement on Housing.
    Tab 7 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpt from October 16, 1958 remarks at Kiwanis Luncheon.
    Tab 8 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpt from October 19, 1958 campaign proposals' summary statement.
    Tab 9 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 7, 1959.
    Tab 10 Press Release, February 15, 1959 -- Statement on funds appropriated in the Budget for the aging, the blind, the disabled, and dependent children, February 15, 1959.
    Tab 11 Proclamation - Senior Citizens Month, May 15, 1959
    Tab 12 Press Release, July 31, 1959 -- Statement appointing Committee to analyze hospital facilities and medical care programs in New York, July 31, 1959.
    Tab 13 Press Release, August 26, 1959 -- Statement on appointment of consultant to New York State Committee for the White House Conference on Aging, September 1, 1959.
    Tab 14 Press Release, September 30, 1959 -- Address to Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York, New York City, September 29, 1959.
    Tab 15 Press Release, December 1, 1959 -- Address at Little White House Conference on Aging, on Role of Aging, New York City, December 1, 1959.
    Tab 16 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller and Legislative Leaders on conversion of group health insurance for senior citizens, March 24, 1960.
    Tab 17 Press Release, March 24, 1960 -- Joint Statement by Governor Rockefeller and Legislative Leaders on conversion of group health insurance for senior citizens, March 24, 1960.
    Tab 18 Press Release, March 29, 1960 -- Special Message to the Legislature on health insurance for senior citizens, March 18, 1960.
    Tab 19 Press Release, April 4, 1960 -- Executive Order Establishing an Interdepartmental Health and Hospital Council, March 31, 1960.
    Tab 20 Press Release, April 30, 1960 -- Veto Memorandum on Assembly Bill Int. 3203, Pr. 3268, requiring supervision by Social Welfare of facilities for the aged, April 29, 1960.
  - Volume 1 - The Aging, 1958-1962 (Box 24, Folder 130)
    Tab 21 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters 819, 820, 1960 Executive Budget.
    Tab 22 NAR Statement: Health Care for the Aged, June 29, 1960 -- brochure of NAR remarks presented at the Governors Conference, Glacier National Park, Montana.
    Tab 23 NAR Statement -- excerpt from NAR Statement to Republican National Platform Committee on "Welfare," July 9, 1960.
    Tab 24 Press Release, September 19, 1960 -- Address at Statewide meeting of Committee of One Hundred for 1961 White House Conference on Aging on "Progress on Solving Problems of the Aging," Albany, September 19, 1960.
    Tab 25 "The Added Years," report of the New York State Committee of One Hundred for the 1961 White House Conference On Aging
    Tab 26 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 27 Press Release, January 4, 1961 -- TV Address on medical program for senior citizens, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 28 Press Release, January 18, 1961 -- transcript of statewide telecast, Senate majority Leader, and Commissioner of Health on medical assistance for senior citizens, January 18, 1961.
    Tab 29 Press Release, March 29, 1961 -- NAR Statement on availability of $50 million in loan funds tax exemptions for housing for aging citizens and establishment of Office of Housing for the Aging, March 29, 1961.